[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
tricentis tasa automation tutorial as
you all know I've already published 72
YouTube videos covering beginners level
intermediate level and advanced level
concepts of PR and tasa test automation
from few videos onwards I've started
teaching you the realtime scenarios
where you might encounter different
types of obstacles and how can we solve
those obstacles while automating your
test
cases please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos don't forget to like and share
the video thank
you this is our lesson 73 in terms of
overall tricentis task automation
tutorial and this is our obstacle 31 in
terms of realtime scenarios this session
I'm going to teach you how can we solve
an obstacle where you need to select a
random item from the drop- down list or
the combo box based on the random text
that is generated in your application so
now let us see in detail what is the
obstacle that we are going to solve for
so here is the obstacle list that we are
working from past few videos so today's
obstacle is the obvious and which is
categorized as easy so let us go for
it it says Generate random string and
select it in the combo box below
so to generate the random string you
need to click on this button which
generates the random string and then you
need to
select this random string from the drop-
down so if you see the drop down you
will have the same random string here so
which one I think this is first one so
you can select this and submit it that
means your automation problem solve
successfully so let me again try again
okay if I generate ramda text now you
can see this is
pk0 G right now let go here and which is
second one I think yeah yeah this is
second drop down so you can select this
second drop down and
submit so that means our automation
problem successfully completed now let
us see how can we
automate this particular scenario or how
how can we solve this obstacle for that
let us go to trien TSA as usual we are
going to scan the application to capture
the objects or elements that are
required for this scenario for that
right click on this obstacles module
folder select scan
application select the application that
is required and then click on
scan so here now we need to Select 1 2 3
4 total four objects needs to be
selected the first one is Generate
random
text and then you need to
capture the generated random
text and then the combo box this one
choose obstacle course and then submit
button so all of these are If You
observe at the bottom all of these are
uniquely identified right you can see
selected item is unique so now let us
rename the module with the name of
obstacle so copy
this and then paste it
here and now save the
module and close
xcan and then let us go to prent tasa
and if you scroll down to the bottom so
this is the module that we have captured
just now double click on this to see all
the objects that we captured are
displaying here not 1 2 3 4 we have now
so now we are done with capturing all
the objects that are required for the
Automation and now let us come to the
left section of test case section which
is blue section here under obstacles
folder let us create a new test case
right click on obstacle
folder select create test case and name
this with the same name of
obstacle and now double click on this
test case so to automate the test case
we need to drag and drop this module
just drag and drop
here so what is our first action that we
need to perform first action is we need
to click on Generate random text so here
let us rename this as Generate
random
text so here you need to click on this
button so enter X here so once that is
done I want to again drag and drop the
module again onto the test
case so then what we need to do we need
to buffer the text whatever the
generated text that we have here that
needs to be buffered we need to store
into a variable so for that what I'm
going to do here I'm going to write
buffer the
generated
random
text okay now here to buffer the
generated random text come
here select inner
text and name this as random
text I'm storing the inner text into a
buffer so here your action mode should
be
buffer so this is done so what is our
next action next action is you need to
select the same value that is displaying
here so here you need to select the same
value this one right for that again drag
this module and drop onto your t test
case now here what I'm going to do I'm
going to rename this
as
select
combo box
item with random
text with above random text I'll say
okay so here what we need to do here
this is our select box so basically this
obstacle is very easy to solve but why
I'm teaching this because you encounter
this kind of scenarios many times in
real time okay so here now to select the
drop down value from the combo box what
we are going to do I'm going to Simply
call this random text
buffer here how can I call here I can
simply open curly braces capital B open
Square braces random text close Square
braces close curly
braces so here I'm selecting the value
from the drop down which is equal to the
value that I have stored in the
buffer and then you need to click on
submit button let's again drag and drop
here the same
module and here rename this
as click
submit
button expand
this and here you need to select submit
which is you need to pass
X once that is done now
our automation is completed basically
what we are doing we are using this
module multiple times because it is
recommended not to use parameters at a
time for single module so that's why we
are calling this module multiple times
and Performing each action in different
modules first I'm generating the text
and then I'm storing the generated text
into buffer and then I'm selecting the
item from the combo Box by using the
buffer value and then I'm clicking on
submit button now let us change the work
state as completed
and now save the test case before we run
the test I think we are making one
mistake here so here this is actually
your random text directly so here I need
not to take the inner text for this okay
so I can directly take the random text
basically the text whatever it is
appearing I can store this into a buffer
called random text why because this is
actually a text box I'm simply buffering
this
text into a buffer so that's why I'm I
can directly specify the buffer name and
select the action mode as buffer so
that's the small modification that we
need to do and now save this and now let
us run the text before running the
text again let us go back to application
and click on try
again now let us run the test and see if
it runs successfully right click and
then run in
scratchbook perfect so you can see here
now it generated and in selected the
drop down value let us run one more time
to make sure it works for every random
text right click and run in the
scratchbook
perfect so you can see here
now it
basically selected the item from drop-
down which is equal to this text so this
is how you can solve the obstacle so if
you have any queries leave your queries
in the comment box I'll try to respond
to your queries thank you hope you all
understand how can we solve an obstacle
where you need to generate the random
text
and you have to buffer that random text
so that you can use the buffered value
to select an item from the combo box
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos please don't forget to like and
share the video thank you
[Music]